<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[lasse.tech]]></title><description><![CDATA[Writing about technology and society from Berlin.]]></description><link>https://lasse.tech</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 19:57:20 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[On veganism]]></title><description><![CDATA[The other day I was siting in the kitchen in my co-working space and ate my lunch with my colleague, who also happens to be an longtime…]]></description><link>https://lasse.tech/on-veganism/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lasse.tech/on-veganism/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The other day I was siting in the kitchen in my co-working space and ate my lunch with my colleague, who also happens to be an longtime vegan. And naturally somewhat devout, because else you simply can&apos;t bear the cost and the hassle of sticking with a vegan diet. You need strong conviction. Indeed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/3039505/the-vast-majority-of-vegetarians-and-vegans-eventually-return-to-meat&quot;&gt;80% of vegetarians and vegans revert back into eating meat&lt;/a&gt;. At the lunch table my colleague were mixing multiple lemons with liters of water for him to hydrate and more important ensure he gets his daily nutrients, specially C-vitamins. Often a hassle for vegans who has do live without nutritional meats and milk products. Afterwards he pulled out his medicine cabinet where he kept his impressive selection of dietary supplements, pills, capsules and powder. A passerby noted it looked like his grand-moms pill collection, which was amusing and spot on. It seemed strange, well practically sick, that a young person would need to eat that amount of pills without going through serious medical treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I forgot about this causal everyday experience until I talked with a girl at a party. She just moved to Berlin and works as an au pair. She have become vegan as she noted at the very beginning of our conversation. Experienced have taught me that such statements, means that one have accept this dogma to continue the conversation in good spirits. I quietly obliged. The next few days it kept coming back to me, I felt that I have been preached to and that I need to decide upon the merits of it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I am learning German at the moment I try to read as much as possible in German, so I looked up the German Wikipedia for &lt;a href=&quot;https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Veganismus&quot;&gt;&quot;Veganismus&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. And it struck me just how different the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Veganism&quot;&gt;English&lt;/a&gt; and German Wikipedias are. In the Anglospehere veganism are recommend and in the Germanosphere it is specially discouraged (perhaps in all of continental Europe). Most notably has the American Dietetic Association (ADA) outright recommends vegan diets:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the position of the Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics that appropriately planned vegetarian, including vegan, diets are healthful, nutritionally adequate and may provide health benefits for the prevention and treatment of certain diseases. These diets are appropriate for all stages of the life cycle, including pregnancy, lactation, infancy, childhood, adolescence, older adulthood and for athletes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ADA even recommends vegan diets for stages of life where nutritional needs are of special importance, such as pregnancy and childhood. This stands in stark contrast to the Germanosphere where the Deutschen Gesellschaft für Ernährung (DGE) states that it is very difficult or outright impossible to get sufficient supply of certain nutrients such as fatty acid or protine. And furthermore the DGE expressly does not recommend vegan diets for pregnant women, nursing mothers, infants, children and young people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The German Wikipedia gives, with multiple references, a detailed and concise breakdown on a per nutrient basis of the potential nutritional dangers. This made only made ADA&apos;s recommendations more incomprehensible, surely there must be an objective truth to be found. I wrote ADA for an explanation and received &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eatrightpro.org/-/media/eatrightpro-files/practice/position-and-practice-papers/position-papers/vegetarian-diet.pdf?la=en&amp;#x26;hash=13D2FB5B600CF0778F6FE12B50ED9CE2645CAEF9&quot;&gt;this complex scientific paper&lt;/a&gt;. After reading it, I momentarily though back at childhood memories of the food pyramid and how accessible and understandable it was. How times have changed, dietary recommendations are now cryptic and beyond reach for the large majority of the population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper goes through some critical nutrients vegan diets lack. It speaks of a &quot;well-planned&quot; vegan diet and offers advice for some nutrients, but it doesn&apos;t present evidence that vegan diets doesn&apos;t in technical terms leads to some sort of malnourishment. It gives complex best practices for vegan supplements on a variety of nutrients, such as n-3 Fatty Acids it states: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The clinical relevance of reduced eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA) and docosahexaenoic acid (DHA) status among vegetarians and vegans is unknown. Long-chain n-3 fatty acids are important for the development and maintenance of the brain, retina, and cell membranes and favorably impact pregnancy outcomes and risk for cardiovascular disease (CVD) and other chronic diseases.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is complex advice for simple dietary recommendations. Does anyone without a doctoral degree know that the daily required dose of n-3 fatty acids are: &quot;The Dietary Reference Intake for ALA are 1.6 g/day and 1.1 g/day, for men and women, respectively&quot; and that these can be supplemented by a &quot;low-dose micro-algae based DHA supplements.&quot; One must presume this means vegans ideally must get their nutrial balance measure regularly to ensure that they get all the needed nutrients. Or ADA puts it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provided that adequate nutrition education is given, a therapeutic vegetarian diet performs as well as omnivorous diets in terms of adherence. As with implementation of any diet, employing a variety of counseling strategies, including motivational interviewing, frequent sessions, cooking demonstrations, and incentives, can improve nutrition-related outcomes when using a vegetarian diet therapeutically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It takes profound effort to live by an ideal vegan diet, to the extend you have to live for it. It sounds almost absurd. It makes one speculate what lies beneath ADA&apos;s recommendation. To me it seems the primary reason for recommending vegan diets is its positive effects on weight-loss and other lifestyle health diseases – which may well be true. The benefits of weight-loss and minimizing the risks of lifestyle diseases outweigh the malnutrition that vegan diets are likely to cause. Extending this recommendation to pregnant and childern seems irresponsible. But given that 39.6% of the US population are obese, I read ADA&apos;s recommendation more as a testimony to the general appalling health situation in the population. It is pragmatism, not hard science. Weight-loss is the deciding factor at the expense of likely malnutrition. Perhaps the German DGE&apos;s recommendation will change if the obese raises from the current 23% of the population to US level.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[My Sublime shortcuts, settings and packages]]></title><description><![CDATA[Shortcuts Reveal in sidebar:  CTRL  +  SHIFT  +  R Select one similar:  CMD  +  D   Select all similar:  CMD  +  CTRL  +  G Select line…]]></description><link>https://lasse.tech/my-sublime-shortcuts-settings-and-packages/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lasse.tech/my-sublime-shortcuts-settings-and-packages/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Shortcuts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reveal in sidebar: &lt;strong&gt;CTRL&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;SHIFT&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select one similar: &lt;strong&gt;CMD&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select all similar: &lt;strong&gt;CMD&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;CTRL&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;G&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select line: &lt;strong&gt;CMD&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;L&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select all child elements: &lt;strong&gt;CMD&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;SHIFT&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;J&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy line: &lt;strong&gt;CMD&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;SHIFT&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switch line: &lt;strong&gt;CMD&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;CTRL&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;↑&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;↓&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toggle sidebar: &lt;strong&gt;CMD&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;K&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close HTML tag &lt;em&gt;(useful for JSX when normal HTML autocomplete doesn&apos;t work)&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;alt&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;CMD&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Configuration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;
      &lt;pre class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;// Hidden from search, but not sidebar&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;binary_file_patterns&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;// Hidden from search and sidebar&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;file_exclude_patterns&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;.DS_store&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;*.map&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;*.min.js&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;*.min.css&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;// Hidden from search and sidebar&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;folder_exclude_patterns&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;.svn&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;.git&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;.hg&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;CVS&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;.sass-cache&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;__pycache__&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;.tmp&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;venv&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;node_modules&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Packages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often work with ES6/React, Node and Python. I use these packages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alienhard/SublimeAllAutocomplete&quot;&gt;All Autocomplete&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facelessuser/BracketHighlighter&quot;&gt;BracketHighlighter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Monnoroch/ColorHighlighter&quot;&gt;Color Highlighter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/spadgos/sublime-jsdocs&quot;&gt;DocBlockr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sindresorhus/editorconfig-sublime&quot;&gt;EditorConfig&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SideBarEnhancements-org/SideBarEnhancements&quot;&gt;SideBarEnhancements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/babel/babel-sublime&quot;&gt;Babel &amp;#x26; Babel snippets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jonlabelle/SublimeJsPrettier&quot;&gt;PrettierJS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/titoBouzout/Dictionaries&quot;&gt;Dictionaries&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Many languages supported.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facelessuser/MarkdownPreview&quot;&gt;Markdown preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Gatsby and React-static]]></title><description><![CDATA[I have been wanting to start a blog for a while now. But I haven't come much further than writing incomplete pieces of text and researching…]]></description><link>https://lasse.tech/gatsby-and-react-static/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lasse.tech/gatsby-and-react-static/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I have been wanting to start a blog for a while now. But I haven&apos;t come much further than writing incomplete pieces of text and researching which blogging tool is the best. It is properly a necessary detour that allows your brain to structure and formulate your thoughts into communicable formats. Writing is fundamentally a different exercise than its precursor – reading – and it takes effort and will to accomplish it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Static React site generators are for me the optimal blogging tool. It leverages technologies I know, is easily customizable and simple. They have the best performance and scalability of any blogging tool and that is while being free. For users with a Git work flow usability is excellent, I can write my blog posts in my favorite editor (Sublime), view it locally and deploy from the command line. You can write with minimal amount of distraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most prominent static React generators are Gatsby and React-static. Both use React and share enough similarities to be considered competitors. In practical use, they differ considerable which is a deliberate choice and this is reflected in the default file structure of both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;React-static&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;npm install -g react-static &amp;amp;&amp;amp; react-static create&lt;/code&gt; and install the basic boilerplate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;
      &lt;pre class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; robots&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;txt
&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; src&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; App&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;js
  &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; app&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;css
  &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; containers&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;404.&lt;/span&gt;js
    &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; About&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;js
    &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Blog&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;js
    &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Home&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;js
    &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Post&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;js
  &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; index&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;js
  &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; logo&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;png
&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;package&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;json
&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;static&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;config&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;js
&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;babelrc
&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;eslintrc&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;js&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With React-static you get the familiar file structure known from &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;create-react-app&lt;/code&gt; with the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;react-static&lt;/code&gt; package added, along with &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;react&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;react-dom&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;react-router&lt;/code&gt;. React-static provides a simple API for attaching data to the React app with the configuration located in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;static.config.js&lt;/code&gt; file. Customization and development are done like a regular React app, no abstractions. There are no &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;react-static&lt;/code&gt; specific plugins, you will need to integrate various Node or React packages when developing features such as: code highlighting, image handling or RSS feed. In this sense, React-static is more a boilerplate or React package leveraging the React technology stack, than an actual static site generator. This is different in Gatsby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gatsby&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;npm i -g gatsby-cli &amp;amp;&amp;amp; gatsby new my-app&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;
      &lt;pre class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; src&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; components&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; header&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;js
  &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; layouts&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; index&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;css
    &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; index&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;js
  &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; pages&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;404.&lt;/span&gt;js
    &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; index&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;js
    &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; page&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt;js
&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; gatsby&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;browser&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;js
&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; gatsby&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;node&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;js
&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; gatsby&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;config&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;js
&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; gatsby&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;ssr&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;js
&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;package&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;json&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gatsby has its own structure and deviates from the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;create-react-app&lt;/code&gt; boilerplate. &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;react&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;react-dom&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;react-router&lt;/code&gt; aren&apos;t in the package.json file – like with React-static – but bundled with Gatsby. Multiple files: &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;gatsby-browser.js&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;gatsby-config.js&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;gatsby-node.js&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;gatsby-ssr.js&lt;/code&gt; gives access to the Gatsby API. This includes adding Gatsby specific plugins or adding custom page types with data, fore instance a blog post template. Gatsby ships with GraphQL for data handling. Beyond the React style used in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;src/&lt;/code&gt; files, there isn&apos;t much evidence that Gatsby is build on React.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Comparison&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gatsby is essentially a static blog generator build on top of React with its own ecosystem, like Wordpress. Building a Gatsby site means using its plugins, API and documentation, not React&apos;s per-se. For blogs, personal or corporate web sites this speeds up development by making image handling, code highlighting or setting up a RSS feed dead simple. The documentation from development to deployment is good and easily accessible from their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/&quot;&gt;web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Gatsby is build on top of React, React-static is build with React. Developing in React-static means developing a React application with data attached to it. It is simple to add data from a data source, but unlike Gatsby it doesn&apos;t come bundled with useful plugins for image handling, attaching files, code highlighting or adding Google analytics. To add such functionality means either coding it yourself or finding an npm package that does this. To add Markdown files as a data source you need to add: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DanWebb/jdown&quot;&gt;jdown&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/paulmillr/chokidar&quot;&gt;chokidar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pveyes/htmr&quot;&gt;htmr&lt;/a&gt; as shown in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nozzle/react-static/tree/master/examples/markdown&quot;&gt;example&lt;/a&gt;. This comes almost build in with Gatsby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose Gatsby for a simple static web site and React-static if you want to add static data to your React app.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>